Fred C. Kelly Papers
Fred C. Kelly Papers
1867-1966
Kelly, Fred C. (Fred Charters), 1882-1959.
6.75 linear ft.
Papers of the American humorist, journalist, author. Collections contains correspondence, 1892-1959; typescript mss. of articles, books, poems, speeches, and stories; notebooks; photographs; and memorabilia, including clippings, drawings, genealogical material, reviews, a scrapbook, and a subject file relating to Orville and Wilbur Wright, of whom Kelly wrote a number of articles and books. Correspondents include, among others, George Ade, Sherwood Anderson, Norman Angell, Newton D. Baker, Nicholas Biddle, Margaret Bourke-White, Bruce Catton, Winston Churchill, Irvin S. Cobb, Homer Croy, Warren G. Harding, Arthur Hosking, John T. McCutcheon, André Maurois, H.L. Mencken, William Sydney Porter (O. Henry), J. B. Priestley, Clarence Rook, Theodore Roosevelt, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, Ida Tarbell, Booth and Susanah Tarkington, Albert Payson Terhune, Harry S. Truman, Wendell Willkie, P.G. Wodehouse, Orville Wright, and Art Young.
149472
Biographical History
Fred Charters Kelly (1882-1959) was an American humorist, newspaperman, columnist and author. From 1910 to 1918 he wrote the first syndicated Washington news column. He was the official biographer of the Wright brothers and was active in the efforts to bring the Kitty Hawk to the Smithsonian Institution from the British Museum in London. He also wrote books on George Ade, Kin Hubbard, and various other subjects, and was the author of numerous magazine articles.
Kelly was born in 1882 in Xenia, Ohio and graduated from public school there before attending the University of Michigan from 1900 to 1902. He began his newspaper career at the age of 14 as a local correspondent for a small town newspaper, and then authored a humorous column for the Cleveland Plain Dealer for five years. During his early years in Washington, while writing his column "Statesmen, Real and Near," he began contributing special articles to leading magazines. For 18 months during World War I, he served as special agent for the Federal Bureau of Investigation. After the war, Mr. Kelly bought and operated a farm in Peninsula, Ohio, continued free-lance writing, and began his career as an author. His works include Human Nature in Business (1920), How to Lose Your Money Prudently (1933), The Wright Brothers (1943), and George Ade - Warm Hearted Satirist (1947).
Kelly was a member of the National Press Club, Overseas Writers Club, and the Players Club. He had a son, Fred C. Kelly Jr., with his first wife; with his second wife, Marcelle van den Heuvel, whom he married in 1938, he had two children, Brian and Jeanne.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Fred C. Kelly Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, photographs, and material relating to the Wright brothers. Each of these categories is further subdivided as shown in the shelf list.
Correspondence relates to Kelly's various interests and writings and to personal matters. His correspondents include George Ade, Claude Bowers, Andre Maurois, Max Lerner, William Borah, William Sydney Porter, Warren Harding, 0.0. McIntyre, and E.L. Mencken. Included are more than one hundred letters from Booth Tarkington (1918-1945). Mr. Kelly's letters from Orville and Milton Wright are separated from this category and filed with the Wright brothers material. The scrapbook of clippings in Oversize 1 also contains some correspondence, including that of Henry Allen, Governor of Kansas, and George Ade.
Subject files include ephemera, biographical and genealogical material, drawings and newspaper clippings, both loose and compiled in a scrapbook.
Writings includes manuscripts, proof sheets and printed copies of articles; books; notebooks; notes; outlines; a playlet; poems; short stories; and speeches.
Photographs includes pictures of Mr. Kelly, his family and friends.
The subject of the Wright brothers was important to Mr. Kelly. In addition to writing a book, The Wright Brothers, and various articles, Kelly was also the editor of a book of letters, Miracle at Kitty Hawk (1951), and How We Invented the Airplane, by Orville Wright. Wright Brothers material includes letters to Mr. Kelly from Orville and Milton Wright; photostatic copies of correspondence of the Wrights with each other and to and from others; diagrams; legal documents; photographs and writings by and about the Wrights.
German and French political posters (1934-1936) and an etching mentioned in the original finding aid cannot be located as of 2/27/09.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author and the outgoing is arranged chronologically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject or type; clippings about and by Mr. Kelly are arranged chronologically, and clippings of reviews of his books are arranged alphabetically by book title. Writings are arranged alphabetically by type; within that, articles and books are arranged alphabetically by title and manuscripts of other authors are arranged alphabetically by author.
Subject and Genre Headings
Biography; Journalism; Literature -- American Fiction; Ade, George, 1866-1944.; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941.; Angell, Norman, 1874-1967.; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.; Biddle, Nicholas, 1893-; Blythe, Samuel George, 1868-1947.; Bok, Edward William, 1863-1930.; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940.; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971.; Bowers, Claude Gernade, 1879-1958.; Brisbane, Arthur, 1864-1936.; Catton, Bruce, 1899-1978.; Churchill, Winston, Sir, 1874-1965.; Cobb, Irvin S. (Irvin Shrewsbury), 1876-1944.; Croy, Homer, 1883-1965.; Elliott, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1874-1960.; Fitzgerald, Barry, 1888-1961.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Henry, O., 1862-1910.; Hollis, Henry French, 1869-1949.; Hosking, Arthur.; Howe, Will David, 1873-1946.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.; Hull, Josephine, 1877-1957.; Hutton, Graham, 1904-1988.; Insull, Samuel, 1859-1938.; Janis, Elsie, 1889-1956.; Kelly, Fred C. (Fred Charters), 1882-1959.; Kettering, Charles Franklin, 1876-1958.; Klein, Julius, 1901-1984.; Lane, Franklin K.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989.; Leacock, Stephen, 1869-1944.; McCulloch, Carleton Buel, 1871-1949.; McCutcheon, John T. (John Tinney), 1870-1949.; McFarland, Marvin Wilks, 1919-; McIntyre, O. O. (Oscar Odd), 1884-1938.; Maurois, André, 1885-1967.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Moley, Raymond, 1886-1975.; Morgan, Byron.; Mowrer, Paul Scott, 1887-1971.; Nenni, Pietro, 1891-1980.; Peary, Robert E. (Robert Edwin), 1856-1920.; Priestley, J. B. (John Boynton), 1894-1984.; Rook, Clarence, 1862-1915.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944.; Schuster, M. Lincoln (Max Lincoln), 1897-1970.; Snow, Edgar, 1905-1972.; Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1879-1962.; Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944.; Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946.; Tarkington, Susanah, 1870-1966.; Terhune, Albert Payson, 1872-1942.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Webster, Harold Tucker, 1885-1952.; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Wodehouse, P. G. (Pelham Grenville), 1881-1975.; Wright, Orville, 1871-1948.; Young, Art, 1866-1943.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Humorists, American.; Journalists -- United States.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Juvenilia.; Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Photoprints.; Reviews (documents); Scrapbooks.; Authors.; Humorists.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Fred C. Kelly, 1949-1959.
Inventory
- Correspondence, incoming
  See also Scrapbook in Oversize 1.
  - A, B, 1900-1959 (Box 1)
  - Ade, George, 1907; 1909,; 1942 (Box 1)
  - Ade, George, re Kelly's book about, 1946-1950 (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1933-1959 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 1)
  - Angell, Norman, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Newton D., 1916-1923 (Box 1)
  - Beard, Charles (Box 1)
  - Biddle, Nicholas, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Blythe, Samuel G., 1911; 1922 (Box 1)
  - Bok, Edward, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Borah, William E., 1933 (Box 1)
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Claude G., 1936-1957 (Box 1)
  - Brisbane, Arthur, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Burnside, Cameron (Box 1)
  - C, 1907-1950 (Box 1)
  - Catton, Bruce, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Cobb, Irvin S. (Box 1)
  - Corey, Madison (Box 1)
  - Cox, James, 1913; 1920 (Box 1)
  - Croy, Homer, 1958; 1959 (Box 1)
  - D, E, F, 1935-1959 (Box 1)
  - Davis, Robert, 1913-1939 (Box 1)
  - DeWoody, Charles, 1918; 1921 (Box 1)
  - Elliott, Edward C., 1932-1945 (Box 1)
    See also Purdue University (Box 2).
  - Family, See Kelly children (Box 1).
  - Fitzgerald, Barry, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor Co., 1956 (Box 1)
  - G, H, 1900-1958 (Box 1)
  - Gardner, Lester, 1942; 1945 (Box 1)
  - Greene, Franklin L., 1920; 1924 (Box 1)
  - Harcourt, Brace, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Harding, Warren G., 1921; 1922 (Box 1)
  - Henry, O., See Porter, William Sydney (Box 2).
  - Hollis, Henry F., 1938-1948 (Box 1)
  - Hosking, Arthur N., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Howe, Will D., 1945 (Box 1)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Hull, Josephine (Box 1)
  - Hutton, Graham, 1938; 1946 (Box 1)
  - I, J, K, 1917-1950 (Box 1)
  - Insull, Samuel, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Janis, Elsie (Box 1)
  - Kelly children, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Kettering, C.F., 1943; 1946 (Box 1)
  - Klein, Julius, 1933 (Box 1)
  - L, M, 1895; 1907-1959 (Box 1)
  - Lane, Franklin K., 1915 (Box 1)
  - Lasky, Jesse L., 1943 (Box 1)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Leacock, Stephen (Box 1)
  - Lepla, A., 1930 (Box 1)
  - Lerner, Max, 1946 (Box 1)
  - J.B. Lippincott Co., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Little-Brown Co., 1932 (Box 1)
  - MacFarland, Marvin W., 1953; 1958 (Box 2)
  - MacMillan Book Co. (Plagiarism), 1953 (Box 2)
  - Marshall, Thomas R., 1914 (Box 2)
  - Maurois, André (Box 2)
  - Mayfield, Earle B., 1958; 1959 (Box 2)
  - Mayfield, John S., 1959 (Box 2)
    See also Curator's correspondence re Kelly to Mayfield, John S. (Box 3) and Writings: Books: My Father, Santa Claus and Me (Oversize 1).
  - McCulloch, Carlton B., 1944 (Box 2)
  - McCutcheon, John T. (Box 2)
  - McIntyre, O. O. (Box 2)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1928-1945 (Box 2)
  - Moley, Raymond, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Morgan, Byron, 1907-1959 (Box 2)
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott, 1941 (Box 2)
  - [re] My Father, Santa Claus and Me, 1959 (Box 2)
  - N, O, 1909-1956 (Box 2)
  - Nenni, Pietro, 1920-1946 (Box 2)
  - Newton, Byron, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Oumansky, C., 1939-1944 (Box 2)
  - P, R, 1910-1958 (Box 2)
  - Palmer, Frederick, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Peary, Robert E., 1911 (Box 2)
  - Phillips, John Sanburn, 1943; 1945 (Box 2)
  - Porter, William Sydney (O. Henry) (Box 2)
    See also Writings: Articles by Kelly: "Concerning Mr. O. Henry" (Box 9).
  - Priestly, John B. (Box 2)
  - Purdue University, 1933; 1946 (Box 2)
    See also Elliott, Edward C. (Box 1).
  - Putnam, G. P., 1928; 1929 (Box 2)
  - Reed, Thomas R., 1942 (Box 2)
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1945-1952 (Box 2)
  - Romain, Jules, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Rook, C.A., 1912; 1913 (Box 2)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr., 1941 (Box 2)
  - S, T, 1900-1958 (Box 2)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1911 (Box 2)
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1938-1948 (Box 2)
  - Snow, Edgar, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Stanley, Lee, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1939-1958 (Box 2)
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1915 (Box 2)
  - Tarbell, Ida M., 1897; 1925 (Box 2)
  - Tarkington, Booth
    - 1918-1945, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Typescript copies, 1923-1945 (Box 3)
    - Duplicates of Tarkington material, 1918-1945 (Box 22-24)
  - Tarkington, Susanah, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Terhune, Albert Payson, 1925 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1957 (Box 3)
  - U, V, W, Y, 1915-1956 (Box 3)
  - Vail Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Webster, Harold T., 1921-1943 (Box 3)
  - West, Rebecca, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Willkie, Wendell, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Wodehouse, P.G., 1947-1958 (Box 3)
  - Woodring, Harry H., 1955 (Box 3)
  - Young, Art, 1934-1943 (Box 3)
  - Unidentified, 1911-1959 (Box 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1941-1959; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Curator's correspondence re Kelly to Mayfield, John S., 1958-1968 (Box 3)
    See also Mayfield, John S. (Box 2).
- Subject files
  - Addresses, calling cards, names, 1893; 1954 (Box 4)
  - Ade, George, holograph manuscript in French (Box 4)
  - Advertisements re Kelly's works, 1911-1952 (Box 4)
  - Air flight, 1943-1957 (Box 4)
  - Animals, 1913-1959 (Box 4)
  - Articles by others, A-W, unknown, 1927-1953 (Box 4)
  - Bicycle craze, 1888-1896; 1953-1955 (Box 4)
  - Biographical material, 1905; 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Book list, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Brochures and handbooks, 1940-1957 (Box 4)
  - Charters family, genealogy, 1881 (Box 4)
  - Clippings
    - About Kelly, 1909-1956; undated (Box 4)
    - By Kelly, 1904-1956; undated (Box 5)
    - By and about others, 1910-1957 (Box 5)
    - Duplicates, 1909-1956; undated; clippings about Kelly (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook, 1920-1930; mostly clippings about Kelly, also contains a few items of correspondence (Oversize 1)
  - Book reviews of books by Kelly
    - David Ross, Modern Pioneer, 1946 (Box 5)
    - The Fun of Knowing Folks, 1923 (Box 5)
    - George Ade - Warm Hearted Satirist, 1947 (Box 5)
    - How Shrewd Speculators Win, 1932 (Box 5)
    - How to Lose Your Money Prudently, 1933 (Box 5)
    - The Life and Times of Kin Hubbard, 1952; 1953 (Box 5)
    - One Thing Leads to Another, 1936 (Box 6)
    - The Permanent Ade, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Why You Win or Lose, 1930 (Box 6)
    - The Wisdom of Laziness, 1924 (Box 6)
  - Book reviews by Kelly, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Letters to the editor, by Kelly, 1941-1958 (Box 6)
  - Play reviews re "Kin Hubbard," based on biography by Kelly, 1951 (Box 6)
  - College course outlines, printed, 1900 (Box 6)
  - Curator's file, 1959; 1968 (Box 6)
    See also Curator's correspondence re Kelly to Mayfield, John S. (Box 3).
  - Drawings, original of and about Kelly, 1919-1943 (Box 6)
  - Etching (missing as of 2/26/09) (Oversize 1)
  - European Trips, 1926-1929; 1932-1938 (Box 6)
  - Farm records, Akron, Ohio, 1913-1955 (Box 6)
  - Financial, 1901-1957 (Box 6)
  - Government publications, 1947-1955 (Box 6)
  - Hat / Churchill memorabilia
    - Hat, autographed by Churchill, and associated photograph (Box 6A)
    - Related correspondence, manuscripts and printed material, 1901-1966 (Box 6)
  - Hubbard, Kin (Box 7)
  - Hosking, Arthur N., 1898; 1948 (Box 7)
  - Kelly family, 1867-1897 (Box 7)
  - Laughhead, Bill, drawings (Box 7)
  - Legal documents, 1911-1947 (Box 7)
  - Medal, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Membership cards, 1913-1939 (Box 7)
  - Memorial service and death notices, for Kelly, May 1959 (Box 7)
  - Newton, Byron Rufus, 1917 (Box 7)
  - Personal items of Kelly (Box 8)
  - Plagiarism, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Poster, Original finding aid also lists French and German posters; these are missing as of 2/27/09 (Oversize 1)
  - Programs, 1900-1955 (Box 8)
  - Russian trip, 1933; 1934 (Box 8)
  - Stationery (Box 8)
  - Tarkington, Booth, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Weather, 1954 (Box 8)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Ambassador as Democrat" printed in Esquire, April, 1937 (Box 9)
    - "An American Promoter" printed in Coronet, November, 1936 (Box 9)
    - "Are You the Right Mr. Ross?" printed in Woman's World Magazine, 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "The Astrology Nonsense" (Box 9)
    - "At Last the Pre-fabs are Here" (Box 9)
    - "Battling for Beauty" printed in The Land (Box 9)
    - "Been Playing the Market" printed in Cosmopolitan, September, 1928 (Box 9)
    - "Beyond College by Armchair" printed in Coronet, September, 1939 (Box 9)
    - "Bill Nye Found Humor in Laramie" printed in The Westerners, 1956 (Box 9)
    - "Bill Nye's Humor" printed in The Quarterly Review, Autumn, 1947; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Booth Tarkington Tells Why Our Young Folks Are So Wild" printed in Colliers, photostat, July 28, 1923 (Box 9)
    - "A Boy Who Hated School" printed in Colliers, Oct. 6, 1923 (Box 9)
    - "Business Profits and Human Nature" printed in Japanese, 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Can You Escape Rheumatism?" printed in Coronet, December,1939 (Box 9)
    - "Can Your Dog Reason?" printed in The Dearborn Independent, June 18, 1927 (Box 9)
    - "Capitalizing Vanity" printed in Saturday Evening Post, September 16, 1916 (Box 9)
    - "Charles F. Brush" Printed in Quarterly Review, 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Chic Sale Makes Us Laugh At Ourselves" printed in The American Magazine, 1923; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Clues We All Leave" (Box 9)
    - "College for Cops" printed in Coronet, January 1941 (Box 9)
    - "College Thoughts After Twenty Years" printed in The Michigan Chimes, December 1921; 3 copies (Box 9)
    - "The Commercial Genius of 'Worms Jones'" (Box 9)
    - "Common Mistakes in Making a Will" (Box 9)
    - "Concerning Mr. O. Henry", 1910; typescript essay, includes letter from Clarence L. [last name illegible] (Box 9)
    - "Conversational Sample" printed in Esquire, March, 1936 (Box 9)
    - "A Date With Destiny" (Box 9)
    - "Detectives Can Guess Our Behavior" (Box 9)
    - "Dictaphone Episode" (Box 9)
    - "Discovering the Plans of Old Ironsides", 1956; 6 copies (Box 9)
    - "Do Men Marry Red Hair?" printed (Box 9)
    - "Do We Like to be Fooled?" printed in Cosmopolitan, March, 1921; 3 copies (Box 9)
    - "Do You Really Know About Things?" printed in The American Magazine (Box 9)
    - "Ever Try to Stand on Two Feet?" (Box 9)
    - "Explaining Your Dogs Behavior" The Dearborn Independent, June 4, 1927; proof copy; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Fallacies Nobody Questions" (Box 9)
    - "A Famous Spy Case of the F.B.I." (Box 9)
    - "Financial Bubbles Ancient and Modern" (Box 9)
    - "Flying the First Plane" printed in Catholic Digest, 1951 (Box 9)
    - "Following the Crowd" printed in The Saturday Evening Post, July 21, 1917 (Box 9)
    - "Foolish Questions Asked in Schools" printed in The American Magazine (Box 9)
    - "Footsteps in Times Square" (Box 9)
    - "Forecasting Honesty" (Box 9)
    - "Forecasting Your Marriage Risks" (Box 9)
    - "For Clearer Thinking" (Box 9)
    - "Foretelling Human Behavior", 3 versions (Box 9)
    - "Foretelling Our Theatrical Tastes" (Box 9)
    - "Funny Adventures of a Smoker Abroad" printed in Every Week Magazine, 1935 (Box 9)
    - "The French Are Polite" reprint from Esquire, December, 1939; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "George Ade, Master of Warm Hearted Satire" printed in Michigan Alumnus, 1955 (Box 9)
    - "Getting the Site for the Rockefeller Center", 1958; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Giving the Youngsters a Chance" printed in The Commentator (Box 9)
    - "The Gloom of Humor" printed in Harper's (Box 9)
    - "The Greatest Cause of Disability", 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Handwriting and Murder", 2 copies (Box 9)
    - "Have We Enough Stupidity?" printed in The Commentator (Box 9)
    - "Have You an Almanac or Only a Thermometer?", reprint (Box 9)
    - "Have You a Put or Call?" (Box 9)
    - "He Gets Acquainted" (Box 10)
    - "Hotel Men Know What to Expect", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "How Detectives Work", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "How Does a Detective Trail His Man?" printed in Ladies Home Journal, March, 1919 (Box 10)
    - "How Fast Can You Think Straight?" (Box 10)
    - "How Five Dollars Started a Revolution" (Box 10)
    - "How General Marshall Became Chief of Staff", 2 versions (Box 10)
    - "How Long Can You Live?", 1921 (Box 10)
    - "How Perseverance Caught a Spy" (Box 10)
    - "How Tecumseh Brought in Prosperity" (Box 10)
    - "How Tecumseh Transformed Itself", 3 copies (Box 10)
    - "How to Choose the Right Stocks" (Box 10)
    - "How to Handle Problem Children" (Box 10)
    - "How to Protect Your Innards Diplomatically", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "How to Recognize Liars" (Box 10)
    - "How to Simplify Life" (Box 10)
    - "How to Spot Liars" (Box 10)
    - "Human Nature in Business" printed in Japanese (Box 10)
    - "I, Being of Sound Mind," printed in Nation's Business, May, 1948 (Box 10)
    - "I Sold Gold Bricks to Bankers", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "I Was a Funny Man," printed copy, The Commentator (Box 10)
    - "If You Want to Manage People," printed in Your Life, 1943 (Box 10)
    - "In My Home Town", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "I'd Like to Try it Over" (Box 10)
    - "Inflation - What is It?" (Box 10)
    - "Inspecting a Harem" (Box 10)
    - "International Finance" (Box 10)
    - "Is Better Health Due to the Doctors?" printed in The New York Times Current History, 1923 (Box 10)
    - "Is the Supreme Court a Court?" (Box 10)
    - "It Isn't Easy to Disappear", 2 versions (Box 10)
    - "It Sometimes Happens" (Box 10)
    - "It's Easy to Fool People" (Box 10)
    - "Jokes That Tickled Grandpa", 3 copies (Box 10)
    - "Kin Hubbard Has Won Fame By Writing Two Sentences a Day" printed in The American Magazine (Box 10)
    - "Know Your Own Talents," printed in Coronet, October, 1944 (Box 10)
    - "Lawyers and Liars" printed in Coronet, September, 1938 (Box 10)
    - "Learn to Think Straight" printed in Your Life, 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "A Life of John D. Rockefeller", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "Love in the Gay Nineties", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "Mail Order Companies Outguess the Customers,", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "Making Friends as a Business Asset," printed in Leslie's Weekly, November 6, 1920 (Box 10)
    - "The Man Who Played Too Much" printed in McClure's, January, [1919] (Box 10)
    - "A Man Who Wouldn't Make Enemies," printed in McClure's, December 1919 (Box 10)
    - "The Man Who Wouldn't Make Friends" printed in McClure's, November, 1919; 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "Man's Triumph Over the Prostate" printed in Esquire, November; 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "A Master At Spotting Fraud", 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "Mastering Appearance With Color Schemes," printed in People's Favorite Magazine, 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "Misunderstood Moscow" printed in Coronet, February, 1937 (Box 10)
    - "Monkey Sense," printed in Coronet, August 1938 (Box 10)
    - "The Most Famous Patent Case," printed in Michigan Alumnus, 1957; 2 copies (Box 10)
    - "My Adventure in Surgery," printed in a pamphlet, 3 copies (Box 10)
    - "My Battle Against Roadside Eyesores" (Box 10)
    - "My Bout With Santa Claus," printed in Coronet, December, 1943 (Box 10)
    - "My Discovery of a Great Humorist" (Box 10)
    - "My Friend 'Chic Sale'" (Box 10)
    - "My Struggle For Compactness," printed copy (Box 10)
    - "Myths of Aviation" (Box 10)
    - "New Soaps and Old Habits" (Box 10)
    - "A New Plague,", 1952 (Box 10)
    - "Oldest and Biggest Fake - Astrology" (Box 10)
    - "Our Number Prejudices" (Box 10)
    - "Overcoming the Objections to Being Human," printed in Cosmopolitan, April, 1922 (Box 11)
    - "A Path to Clearer Thinking," printed in Coronet, June, 1939 (Box 11)
    - "A Patriotic Burglary,", 1957; 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "Phone Companies Have Your Number,", 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "A Plea For Fat Gals" (Box 11)
    - "Postal Inspectors Get Their Man" (Box 11)
    - "Predicting How Weather Affects Us,", 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "Predicting Customers' Behavior,", 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "Predicting Success at Salesmanship,", 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "A Primer of Economics," printed in Esquire, November, 1935 (Box 11)
    - "A Psychic Mystery of Aviation," printed in Michigan Alumnus, 1958; 3 copies (Box 11)
    - "Psychology of Shoppers' Behavior,", 2 copies (Box 11)
    - "A Quick Glimpse at Ireland," printed (Box 11)
    - "Reflections on Farming," printed in The American Mercury (Box 11)
    - "Rhode Island Postpones Its Resolution" (Box 11)
    - "Royal Historian of Oz," printed in Michigan Alumnus, 1953; 2 copies (Box 11)